Forrest J Ackerman Papers
Forrest J Ackerman Papers
1924-1977
Ackerman, Forrest J.
96 linear ft.
THIS COLLECTION IS CURRENTLY CLOSED FOR PROCESSING. Papers of the American science fiction author, editor, agent, collector and fan. Correspondence, 1930-1967, includes fan mail; communications with other writers including Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, Andre Norton, and others; correspondence with book and film companies. Files, 1951-1967, contain personal financial records and material on various organizational affiliations. Manuscript material, 1962-1969, includes that of Ackerman and others for whom he acted as agent. Published material, 1933-1967, relates to science fiction and includes catalogs, work lists, booklets, clippings, and references.
148795
Biographical History
THIS COLLECTION IS CURRENTLY CLOSED FOR PROCESSING.
Forrest J Ackerman (no period after the middle initial) was born November 24, 1916 in Los Angeles, California. He saw his first fantasy film at age five and from that moment on his life and work was built around science fiction as fan, author, agent, publisher, editor and collector.
In 1923, at the age of seven, he was a charter member of the Science Fiction League and in 1930 he created The Boys' Scientifiction Club. In 1939 he attended the First World Science Fiction Convention, where he wore the first "futuristicostume" and sparked a tradition of fan costuming that continues to this day at science fiction conventions around the world; he has missed only two WorldCons in the ensuing 70 years. In 1946 he founded the Fantasy Foundation and helpd found the Los Angeles Science Fantasy Society and the National Fantasy Fan Federation (N3F). In 1953 he received a unique Hugo Award for "#1 Fan Personality."
His writing began almost as early as his fan activities -- in 1929, when he won a contest at the San Francisco Chronicle with his original story of a trip to Mars. Since then, fifty of his stories have been published, including collaborations with A. E. van Vogt, Francis Flagg, Robert A. W. Lowndes, Marion Zimmer Bradley, Donald Wolheim and Catherine Moore, and his stories have been translated into six languages. He named and wrote the origin story for the title character of the Vampirella comic book series. In addition, he has ten non-fiction books (most on science fiction movies) and thirteen anthologies to his credit. His known pseudonyms include SF Balboa, Nick Beal, Walter Chinwell, J. Forrester Eckman, Jacques De Forest Erman, Laurajean Ermayne, Jone Lee Heard, Alus Kerlay, Alden Lorraine, Jack Parish, Spencer Strong, Fisher Trentworth, Allis Villette, Hubert George Wills, Weaver Wright, and Dr. Acula.
In addition to his own writing, Ackerman inspired or assisted many other future luminaries of the genre, including Ray Bradbury (whose first story was published by Ackerman), Ray Harryhausen, Charles Beaumont, Marion Zimmer Bradley, Stephen King (whose first story submission was to Ackerman's Spacemen magazine) and L. Ron Hubbard. He has represented some 200 science fiction and fantasy authors, including Hugo Gernsback, Andre Norton, A.E. van Vogt, and Jack Williamson, and was Ed Wood's "illiterary" agent. Ackerman is also credited with having coined the term "sci-fi" in 1954.
Ackerman edited, published, or otherwise assisted a number of science fiction magazines over the years, creating and inspiring a legion of fans. At the tender age of sixteen he became associate editor of Time Traveller magazine, the first-ever fanzine, and the next year became film editor of Science Fiction Digest. In 1939 he started his own magazine, Voice of Imagination, and later edited Famous Monsters of Filmland, Monster World, and Spacemen. He provided publishing assistance to The Daughters of Bilitis in the group's early days (that, and his several lesbian novels written under the name "Laurajean Ermayne," earned him the title of "honorary lesbian").
His love of the genre is not limited by national borders, as evidenced by his active contributions to film magazines from around the world, including the Argentinian La Cosa - Cine Fantástico, where he had a monthly column for over four years. In 1960, he introduced American readers to the longest science fiction series in history when he organized Ace Books' publication of an English translation of the German science fiction series Perry Rhodan (much of the translation was done by his German wife, Wendayne).
Over the years Ackerman amassed a comprehensive collection of science fiction, fantasy and horror film material amounting to some 300,000 items: books (including 500 editions of Frankenstein and Dracula), magazines, videos, photographs, clippings, manuscripts, autographs, toys, and movie memorabilia (among which is the head of The Creature from the Black Lagoon and a Martian death-ray machine from War of the Worlds). Until 2002 the collection resided in the 18-room "Ackermansion" in the Los Feliz district of Los Angeles; he later donated a number of items to the Seattle Science Fiction Museum and Hall of Fame, of which he is a board member. Among his friends are icons of the genre including Fritz Lang, Bela Lugosi, Vincent Price, and Boris Karloff, and he has made cameo appearances in more than fifty films.
His efforts across a broad spectrum of the arts not only encouraged the organization and spread of science fiction and its fans, but also did much to foster the acceptance of science fiction as a respectable literary, art and film genre. He has truly earned the sobriquet "Mr. Science Fiction."
"I regard myself as a sci-fi sponge that should be squeezed for information and anecdotes as long as I'm here. So while I'm still around, squeeze me."
— Forrest J. Ackerman.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
THIS COLLECTION IS CURRENTLY CLOSED FOR PROCESSING.
The Forrest J Ackerman Papers consists of correspondence, subject files, manuscripts and science fiction material.
Correspondence (18 boxes, 1930-1967) includes incoming correspondence of Forrest J Ackerman, including fan mail and greeting cards, and outgoing correspondence. There is also some correspondence of others. Notable names found in correspondence include Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, Hubbard College of Scientology, Christopher Lee, Andre Norton, Samuel A. Peeples, Robert Silverberg, A.E. Van Vogt, (Manly) Wade Wellman, and Jack Williamson. There is also a large amount of fan mail.
Subject files (2 boxes, 1951-1967) include advertisements, bank and tax forms, correspondence with organizations, clippings, notes, and published material including a book of Ronald Cobb's drawings autographed by the artist and a section on organizations to which Forrest J Ackerman belonged.
Manuscripts (1 box, 1962-1967) contains incomplete drafts of various issues of Famous Monsters and Monster World, manuscripts of several stories and a set of musical lyrics arranged alphabetically by title and subject. This series also includes manuscripts of others arranged alphabetically by author; authors include Isaac Asimov and Harry Harrison.
Science fiction (8 boxes, 1933-1967) is divided into three parts: Related material, Literary material, and Published material. Related material contains correspondence, catalogs, lists and published material relating to Forrest J Ackerman's work as an editor, agent and writer and includes a section of science fiction organizations to which Ackerman belonged. Literary material includes published works of Forrest J Ackerman arranged alphabetically by title of publication. Published material includes booklets, clippings and magazines concerning science fiction, arranged alphabetically by type and then by title; this section includes some foreign-language material.
The collection also includes two later accessions which have not been integrated into the main collection. 1978 additions (64 linear ft) contains a wide range of material, including art, clippings, memorabilia, correspondence, photographs and writings. 1991 additions (0.25 linear ft.) contains writings, published magazines, clippings, and a videotape. See the inventory below for full details.
Note that the two later additions, and each series in the main collection, restart their numbering with "Box 1." When requesting material, please be sure to include the series or accession date and box number to ensure retrieval of the correct items.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is subdivided into incoming and outgoing; incoming general correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the sender and all other correspondence is arranged chronologically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by topic, while manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by title. Science fiction material is arranged alphabetically by type.
Note that each series is numbered separately beginning with "Box 1." Please specify both series and box number when requesting boxes to ensure that the correct items are retrieved.
Related Material
has substantial science fiction related holdings both in its manuscripts collections and in Rare Books. Please refer to for a listing of related manuscript collections and search for a complete list of books.
Subject and Genre Headings
Science fiction; Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Ackerman, Forrest J.; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-2012.; Norton, Alice Mary.; Norton, Andre.; Silverberg, Robert.; Van Vogt, A. E. (Alfred Elton), 1912-2000.; Wellman, Manly Wade, 1903-1986; Wollheim, Donald A.; Science Fiction Writers of America.; World Science Fiction Society.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Editors -- United States.; Fantasy fiction, American.; Novelists, American.; Science fiction, American.; Monsters in mass media.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Magazines.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Authors.; Editors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
THIS COLLECTION IS CURRENTLY CLOSED FOR PROCESSING.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Forrest J Ackerman and Forest J Ackerman Estate, 1967-2010.
Inventory
- CLOSED FOR PROCESSING.
  THIS COLLECTION IS CURRENTLY CLOSED FOR PROCESSING.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming - general
    - A - H, 1947-1967; undated; 9 folders (Box 1)
    - I - S, 1935; 1949,; 1954-1967,; undated; 13 folders (Box 2)
    - T - Z, 1930; 1938,; 1953-1967,; undated; 5 folders (Box 3)
    - Ace Books, Inc., 1957-1967 (Box 3)
    - Ackerman, Carroll, 1956; 1960-1961,; 1963-1967,; undated (Box 3)
    - Albright, Donn, 1967; undated (Box 3)
    - Asimov, Isaac and Robyn, 1956; 1957,; 1961,; 1965-1967 (Box 3)
    - Beaumont, Charles, 1954; 1956,; 1963 (Box 3)
    - Beckman, Peter, 1964-1966; undated (Box 3)
    - Belmont Productions, Inc., 1967 (Box 3)
    - Bennet, Vern, 1966-1967; undated (Box 3)
    - Bogaslawski, Peter, 1963; undated (Box 3)
    - Bradbury, Ray, 1951; 1961,; 1966,; undated (Box 3)
    - Brunas, John and Michael, 1964-1966 (Box 3)
    - Burdick, Lorraine, 1963-1967; undated (Box 3)
    - Carnell, E. J., 1957; 1963-1967 (Box 3)
    - Coburn, William, 1963-1966 (Box 3)
    - Collier, Chris, 1962-1966; undated (Box 3)
    - Coune, Georges, 1965-1967 (Box 3)
    - Cozzi, Luigi, 1965-1967; undated (Box 3)
    - Danials, Gray, 1965-1967; undated (Box 3)
    - Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1963-1967 (Box 4)
    - Edgar Rice Burroughs, Inc., 1963-1967 (Box 4)
    - Edwards, Gary, 1963; 1964,; 1966,; undated (Box 4)
    - Ernsting, Walter, 1957-1967; undated (Box 4)
    - Estes, Oscar, 1963; 1964,; 1966,; 1967,; undated (Box 4)
    - F and S. F. Book Co., 1961-1967; undated (Box 4)
    - Gallet, Georges, 1961-1965 (Box 4)
    - Gardiner, John, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
    - Germehausen, Anna, Louise and Al, 1957; 1963-1964,; undated (Box 4)
    - Gold, Horace, 1965; 1967,; undated (Box 4)
    - Grabner, Boris, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
    - Greenberg, Robert, 1962-1966; undated (Box 4)
    - de Groote, Alexander, 1963; 1965 (Box 4)
    - van Hageland, Albert, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
    - Haussler, Herbert, 1957; 1961-1966,; undated (Box 4)
    - Hubbard College of Scientology, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Jarman, Peter J., 1964-1967; undated (Box 4)
    - Keising, Irving, 1965-1967 (Box 4)
    - Kolchak, Harriet, 1962-1967 (Box 4)
    - Lee, Christopher, undated (Box 4)
    - Levitt, Dan, 1964-1967; undated (Box 4)
    - MacFadden-Bartell Corporation, 1963; 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Mass, Joseph, 1962-1967; undated (Box 4)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Inc., 1965-1967 (Box 4)
    - Michel, Jean-Claude, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
    - Minter, Richard, 1963-1967 (Box 4)
    - Mula, Tom, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Naughton, Peter, 1962-1965 (Box 4)
    - Neutzel, Charles, 1965; 1967,; undated (Box 4)
    - Norton, Andre, 1961; 1965-1967,; undated (Box 4)
    - Obbagy, William, 1962; 1966,; undated (Box 4)
    - Osborne, Charles, 1963; 1967,; undated (Box 4)
    - Paperback Library, Inc., 1963-1967 (Box 4)
    - Partridge, Norman, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Peeples, Samuel A., 1963; 1965-1967 (Box 4)
    - Pfeffer, Max, 1949; 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Pickering, Stephan, 1964-1967; undated (Box 4)
    - de la Ree, Gerald, 1957; 1961-1967,; undated (Box 5)
    - Reed, Dr. Donald A. (President of the "The Count Dracula Society"), 1964-1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Romer, Jean-Claude, 1963-1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Rubin, Samuel "8 MM Collector", 1966; 1967,; undated (Box 5)
    - Scognamillo, Giovanni, 1960; 1965 (Box 5)
    - Silverberg, Robert, 1961; 1966-1967 (Box 5)
    - Tabb, Lamar, 1964-1967 (Box 5)
    - Temple, William, 1959-1967 (Box 5)
    - Trimble, John, 1961; 1964,; 1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Unbehaun, Klaus, 1961; 1963-1966 (Box 5)
    - Vertlieb, Steve and Erwin, 1965-1967 (Box 5)
    - Van Vogt, A. E., 1963-1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Warren, James, 1957-1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Warren, William and Beverly, 1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Wellman, Wade, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
    - Williamson, Jack, 1959-1965 (Box 5)
    - Willits, Malcolm Collectors Bookstore, 1961; 1964-1966,; undated (Box 5)
    - Wollheim, Don Ace Books, Inc., 1958-1967; undated (Box 5)
    - Unidentified, 1942; 1954-1967 (Box 5)
    - Unidentified, 1957; 1963-1967,; undated (Box 5)
  - Incoming - fan mail
    - 1948, 1954-1955, 1958-1962 (Mar), 9 folders (Box 6)
    - 1962, Apr-Dec, 5 folders (Box 7)
    - 1963, Jan-Jul, 5 folders (Box 8)
    - 1963, Jul-Dec, 5 folders (Box 9)
    - 1964, 5 folders (Box 10)
    - 1965, Jan (Box 10)
    - 1965, Feb-Oct, 5 folders (Box 11)
    - 1965, Nov-Dec (Box 12)
    - 1966, 6 folders (Box 12)
    - 1967, Jan-Oct, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Drawings, 1960-1967; undated; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Undated (Box 14)
    - Undated (Box 15)
  - Incoming - greeting cards
    - Undated (Box 16)
    - Birthday, 1966; undated (Box 16)
    - Christmas, 1958; 1966,; undated; 6 folders (Box 16, 17)
    - Get well, undated (Box 17)
    - Telegrams, congratulatory, undated (Box 17)
  - Outgoing
    - 1938 (Box 17)
    - 1949 (Box 17)
    - 1951-1963, 7 folders (Box 17)
    - 1964-1967, 7 folders (Box 18)
    - Undated (Box 18)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 18)
  - Of others, A-Z, 1955-1967; undated (Box 18)
- Subject files
  - Advertisements
    - Miscellaneous, 1962; 1967,; undated (Box 1)
    - Magazines, 1967; undated (Box 1)
    - Organizations, 1958; 1962-1967,; undated (Box 1)
  - Agents report forms, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Announcements, 1955-1966; undated (Box 1)
  - Bank and tax forms, 1960-1967 (Box 1)
  - Bills and receipts, 1962-1967; undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1956; undated (Box 1)
  - Colorado State University Library, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Employment resumes, 1962; undated (Box 1)
  - Evans, Everett, undated (Box 1)
  - Insurance, 1955; 1967,; undated (Box 1)
  - Invitations, 1964-1966; undated (Box 1)
  - Notes, 1965-1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - N. Y. Film Festival, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Organizations
    - Air-A-Tans, 1961; 1962,; undated (Box 2)
    - Book Clubs, 1964; 1967,; undated (Box 2)
    - California Council on Religion and the Homophile, 1966 (Box 2)
    - The Calvin Coolidge Society, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Esperanto
      - Newsletters and correspondence, 1955; 1960-1967,; undated (Box 2)
      - Publications, 1961-1967; undated (Box 2)
    - International Society for General Semantics, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Neo-Fund Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
    - Severance Club, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Programs, 1967; undated (Box 2)
  - Publications, 1958; undated (Box 2)
  - Receipts, 1957; 1961-1967,; undated (Box 2)
  - Ron Cobb drawings, autographed, 1967; 25 drawings (Box 2)
  - Trips, 1951; 1957,; 1959,; 1965,; 1967,; undated (Box 2)
- Manuscripts
  - Famous Monsters
    - Nos. 18, 20, 26, 27 (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
    - Nos. 30, 32, 33, 34 (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
    - Nos. 40-43, 44 (incomplete), 1966; undated (Box 1)
    - No. 46 (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
    - No. 47 (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
    - No. 48 (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 1)
  - "Frankenstein's Bebe?", undated (Box 1)
  - "Frankenstein from Space", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Monster Man, Sire of Slan", undated (Box 1)
  - Monster World Nos. 2, 3, 5, 9, 11 (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
  - Musical Lyrics, Nov-Dec 1964; undated (Box 1)
  - Spaceland (incomplete), undated (Box 1)
  - "When Frighthood Was in Flower", 1967 (Box 1)
  - Fragments, 1967; undated (Box 1)
  - Of others
    - Asimov, Isaac, undated (Box 1)
    - Harrison, Harry, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Obbagy, Bill, 1962; undated (Box 1)
    - Poetry, 1965; undated (Box 1)
    - Translations - Ackerman, Wendayne, undated (Box 1)
    - Various, undated (Box 1)
    - Warren, Bill, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 1)
- Science fiction
  - Related material
    - Ackerman Agency, 1960; 1962,; 1965,; 1967,; undated (Box 1)
    - Advertisements, 1956-1958; 1963-1967,; undated (Box 1)
    - Agreement forms, 1962; 1967,; undated (Box 1)
    - Awards - Japan Science Fiction Fandom Award (Xerox copy), 1967 (Box 1)
    - Big Heart Awards, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Book announcements, 1960; 1965,; 1967,; undated (Box 1)
    - Business cards, undated (Box 1)
    - Copied story, undated (Box 1)
    - Decimal classification of fantasy (Box 1)
    - Russell, Samuel, undated (Box 1)
    - Erb-Dom, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Famous Monsters excerpts, undated (Box 1)
    - Filing cards, undated (Box 1)
    - Letterheads, forms and calling cards, 1967; undated (Box 1)
    - Lists
      - Addresses, 1967; undated (Box 1)
      - Advertisers, undated (Box 1)
      - Agenda of screenplays, Edwards, G. John, undated (Box 1)
      - Articles in various magazines, 1945-1954 (Box 1)
      - Books
        - 1964-1967, undated (Box 1)
        - F & S Book Store, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Fantast (Medway) Ltd., 1959; 1965-1967,; undated (Box 2)
        - G. Ken Chapman Ltd., undated (Box 2)
        - Reston, Ronald, undated (Box 2)
        - Transgalaxis, 1958 (Box 2)
      - Comic books, 1967; undated (Box 2)
      - Clients, undated (Box 2)
      - Films, undated (Box 2)
      - Foreign, 1966-1967; undated (Box 2)
      - International Fantasy Award entries, 1954 (Box 2)
      - Items of house for sale, 1961; 1967,; undated (Box 2)
      - Magazines, undated (Box 2)
      - Movie Star News, 1964; 1966,; undated (Box 2)
      - New York Post reprints, 1955-1957 (Box 2)
      - People, 1967; undated (Box 2)
      - Posters and auction material, undated (Box 2)
      - Problems film classification, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
      - Stills and photos, 1963; 1967,; undated (Box 2)
      - Wanted by Ackerman, Forrest J, 1960; 1967,; undated (Box 2)
      - Various, 1960-1967; undated (Box 3)
      - Unidentified, 1967; undated: (Box 3)
    - Magazine covers, 1954; undated (Box 3)
    - Memos, 1964; 1967,; undated (Box 3)
    - Notes
      - 1962, 1967, undated (Box 3)
      - on Karloff Interview, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Organizations
      - Award Film Club, 1966 (Box 3)
      - The British Peter Cushing Fan Club, 1963 (Box 3)
      - The Count Dracula Society, 1963-1967 (Box 3)
      - Fandom, undated (Box 3)
      - International Movie Collectors Club, 1962 (Box 3)
      - Los Angeles County-Hollywood Museum, 1963 (Box 3)
      - Los Angeles Science Fantasy Society, 1952; 1957,; 1966-1967,; undated (Box 3)
      - National Fantasy Fan Federation, 1963; 1965 (Box 3)
      - Science-Fantasy Writers of America, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Science Fiction Writers of America, 1964-1967; undated (Box 3)
      - Trans-Atlantic Fan Fund, 1962-1965; undated (Box 3)
      - World Science Fiction Society, 1958-1959; 1964-1967,; undated (Box 3)
    - Photos, undated (Box 3)
    - Photos, autographed, undated (Box 3)
    - Publicity, 1952; 1961,; 1965-1967,; undated (Box 3)
    - Receipts
      - 1964-1967, undated (Box 3)
      - G. Ken Chapman Ltd., 1959-1967 (Box 3)
      - H. M. Johnson, 1956-1966 (Box 3)
    - Rejection slips, undated (Box 3)
    - Royalty Statements, 1956-1957; 1962-1966,; undated (Box 3)
    - Scripts, 1965; undated (Box 3)
    - Story synopsis, undated (Box 3)
    - Tax forms, 1951; 1957,; 1959,; 1967 (Box 3)
  - Literary material
    - Adventures in Tomorrow (pub. by Greenberg), "The Mute Question", 1951 (Box 4)
    - The Arkham Sampler, "A Basic Science Library, A Symposium" by Ackerman, Forrest J, and others; "Dr. Keller Again", Winter, 1949 (Box 4)
    - Los Cuentos Fantasticos
      - Vol. 2 #22 "La Pregunta Silente", undated (Box 4)
      - Vol. 3 #6 "No Hay Tiempo Como El Futuro", undated (Box 4)
      - Vol. 3 #25 "Nada Nuero Bajo El Sol", undated (Box 4)
      - Vol. 3 #33 "El Monumento Atomico", undated (Box 4)
    - Famous Monsters of Filmland (excerpts)
      - "The Frankenstein Story", undated (Box 4)
      - "Public Vampire No. 1", undated (Box 4)
    - Fantasy Book
      - Vol. 1 #1 "Strange Alliance", 1947 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 1 #4 "Dwellers in the Dust", Dec, 1948; 3 copies (Box 4)
    - Fantasy Magazine
      - Vol. 2 #6 "Scientifilm Theme Songs", Feb, 1934 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 3 #1 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Mar, 1934 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 3 #4 "Scientifilm Snapshots", Jun, 1934 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 3 #5 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Jul, 1934 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 4 #1 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Sep, 1934 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 4 #2 -"Science Fiction Serial", Oct-Nov, 1934 (Box 4)
      - "Scientifilm Snapshots" (Box 4)
      - Vol. 4 #4 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Feb-Mar, 1935 (Box 4)
      - "Universal languages" (Box 4)
      - Vol. 5 #1 "Scientifilm Snapshots", Jun, 1935 (Box 4)
      - Vol. 5 #3 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Aug, 1935 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 5 #4 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Sep, 1935 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 6 #1 "Scientifilm Snapshots", Jan, 1936 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 6 #2 "Scientifilm Snapshots", Mar, 1936 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 6 #3 "Scientifilms", Jun, 1936 (Box 5)
      - #38 "Scientificinematorially Speaking", Sep, 1936 (Box 5)
    - Glom #6 published by Ackerman, Forrest J, Jan, 1947
      - "Procificon Report" (Box 5)
      - "Scientifilmaticorrespondence" (Box 5)
    - If
      - Vol. 6 #2 "The Odd Genre", Feb, 1956 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 6 #3 "The Odd Genre", Apr, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Imaginative Tales (fragment), "Scientifilm Marquee", undated (Box 5)
    - Marvel Science Stories Vol. 3 #1, "Behind the Ate Ball"; "Race to the Moon"; "Why We Might Have Another World War", Nov, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Nebula Science Fiction
      - Vol. 1 #3 "Scientifilm Previews", Summer, 1953 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 1 #4 "Scientifilm Previews", Autumn, 1953 (Box 5)
      - Vol. 2 #1 "Sabina", undated (Box 5)
      - "Scientifilm Previews (Box 5)
      - Vol. 2 #3 "Scientifilm Previews", Feb, 1954 (Box 5)
    - The New York Post, "Science Fiction", Apr 3, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Other Worlds Science Stories
      - Vol. 2 #2 "The Mute Question", Sep, 1950 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 2 #3 "Earth Can Be Fair" (conclusion), Oct, 1950 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 2 #21 "Scientifilm Searchlight", Mar, 1957 (Box 6)